# CRISTINA BOTTA

MSc in Digital Media and independent researcher | STEAM educator | Graphic and media designer

O Dublin City

+353 83 2005728





# **EDUCATION**

#### University of Bremen / University of the Arts Bremen

MSc in Digital Media

Bremen, DE 2008 - 2011

- Inter-University Study Program in cooperation between the University of Bremen, University of the Arts Bremen, and Universities of Applied Sciences Bremen and Bremerhaven.
- Master project focused on game-based learning, mobile and context aware games, and interaction design
- Master thesis focused on how storytelling structures and the limitations of simulations affect how video games are designed and played.

#### Centro Universitário SENAC

São Paulo, BR

POSTGRADUATE DEGREE IN HIGHER EDUCATION

2012

Dissertation focused on the history, design and use of educational software and games.

#### Centro Universitário Belas Artes de São Paulo

BA IN GRAPHIC DESIGN

Sao Paulo, BR 2001-2005

 Graduation project focused on showing through images and design the importance of play during childhood.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### SESC SP Serviço Social do Comércio

ARTS AND TECHNOLOGY EDUCATOR

São Paulo, BR 05/2012 - 06/2022

- Elaborate and teach workshops, activities and courses on subjects related to arts, culture, technology and digital literacy for all age groups. Promote social inclusion and a meaningful and critical appropriation of the use of technology.
- Write texts for use in the dissemination of activities. Create materials for online activities, including photography and graphics, and editing and narrating videos.
- Research and curate activities, working with invited artists, teachers and specialists
  to adapt these activities taking into consideration the institution's and the public's
  needs.
- Work in collaboration with other teams at SESC in areas such as social development, after school programs, youth group, music, tourism, sports, literature.
- Research new trends in art, media, technology and digital culture.
- Research open source software and hardware for use in art education, digital literacy, digital fabrication, game design, graphic arts, science.
- Decide which new equipment and materials would be needed and acquired.

#### IN2 - AI-powered web solutions

Bremen, DE

JUNIOR CONSULTANT

04/2009 - 09/2009

- Analysis and feedback on user requirements.
- Contribute to the creation of business, dissemination and communication plans.
- Design logos and prepare presentation materials.

#### **Gabler Werbeagentur GmbH**

Stuttgart, DE

JUNIOR DESIGNER

06/2008 - 12/2008

- Design of websites, logos, flyers, mascots, catalogs, and visual identity.
- Flash animations and web banners, and the HTML/CSS part of websites.

#### Lua Branca

São Paulo, BR

TANT 01/2006 - 03/2007

Design of logos and flyers, image treatment, illustration, layout.
Development of Flash websites, animations and web banners.



## **ABOUT ME**

Digital media specialist, interested in digital artifacts preservation and archiving, software and video game studies and history, and the use of technology in education. I have ten years experience working with diverse communities in digital literacy and STEAM in informal education.

## **SKILLS**

Linux

Diverse graphical software

Scratch

HTML-CSS

C

Java

# **LANGUAGES**

English • Fluent
Portuguese • Native
German • Intermediate

# **HOBBIES**

LEGO, drawing and painting, hiking, strategy video games, baking, reading non-fiction from areas completely unrelated to my research. I contribute to some open-source software projects (at the moment only with testing, translations and feedback, but I want to contribute with code in the future).